William Merrow

3214 29th St. Apt 3, Astoria, NY 11106 – william.merrow@gmail.com – 603-568-0366 Portfolio: wmerrow.github.io/

Summary

Information designer with five years of experience creating static and interactive data visualizations for digital publication. Ability to approach projects from creative, technical, and project management standpoints. High attention to detail. Passion for clear graphics and user-centered design.

Skills

data visualization data analysis UX design user research usability testing front-end development project management

Tools

Adobe Illustrator R D3.js HTML & CSS Excel Tableau

Education

Pratt Institute, M.S. in Data Analytics and Visualization expected May 2021

Coursework in data visualization, data journalism, data analysis, D3.js, usability testing, UX

Tufts University, B.A. 2011, *summa cum laude*, Phi Beta Kappa

Major: International Relations, Minor: Sociology

School for International Training, Cochabamba, Bolivia, January to May 2010

Independent coursework:

Intermediate D3 for Data Visualization, Knight Center

Professional Experience

Data Visualization Designer

Council on Foreign Relations, New York, NY November 2018 to present

- Design static and interactive graphics for editorial articles, working with news team to respond to requests and pitch ideas for charts and maps (over 100 graphics in two years)
- Design interactive data tools and static graphics for reports and books, working with senior think tank staff
- Build interactive charts using D3.js and perform quality assurance on interactive web applications
- Lead usability testing and team conversations about data visualization audience and strategy
- Manage data visualization projects and coordinate workload of two-person graphics team to handle assignments simultaneously in a deadline-driven environment
- Update and expand graphic style guide, develop and lead workshops on data visualization best practices

Data Analyst & Visualization Specialist

Graphicacy, Washington, DC September 2015 to October 2018

- Led design of web-based visualizations for major think tank and nonprofit clients, using Adobe Illustrator, Excel, and R to create clear and compelling graphics, working with researchers to ensure visualization design clearly communicated results and accomplished intended goals
- Designed websites, using Sketch to create high quality wireframes and comps in a deadline-based environment
- Led data analysis projects, using R and Excel to manipulate and analyze large datasets
- Managed large projects (\$100k+), managing developers and communicating with client to ensure project success
- Developed and led workshops on data visualization best practices, created data visualization style guide, represented company at conferences and events
- Contributed to business development and strategic planning

Data Visualization with D3, Knight Center Front-end Web Developer Nanodegree, Udacity

Language Skills:

Spanish - intermediate German - proficient

Princeton in Latin America Fellow in Monitoring & Evaluation

The DREAM Project, Cabarete, Dominican Republic August 2014 to August 2015

- Led redesign, migration, and adoption of Salesforce database, creating objects, workflows, reports, and dashboards, using Tableau to visualize student data
- Managed and analyzed student data to assess education programs, identifying trends and ensuring data quality
- Led basic to advanced Excel workshops for all staff; trained managers in use of Salesforce and Tableau
- Managed data and reporting for USAID grant, leading to perfect score on audit of data system

Special Assistant to the President & CEO

InterAction, Washington, DC August 2011 to August 2014

- Coordinated data and communications for \$1.5b food security pledge by 30 international NGOs; prepared data for use in remarks of President Obama and Secretary Clinton
- Authored remarks, blogs, and articles for CEO on range of international development topics; coordinated drafting, editing, and copyediting of 42 policy briefs for flagship publication
- Managed advocacy projects, analyzing legislative language and meeting with congressional staff; managed CEO-level taskforces on aid reform and corporations in international development
- Promoted to Senior Associate level (2012) and Coordinator level (2014)